Guide to the William Richard Johnson Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
William Richard Johnson Papers
1836-1966
RG 6
Yale University Divinity School Library
17.5
(52 boxes)
The papers detail the life and work of William Richard Johnson, most significantly documenting the years he spent in China, 1906-1942. William Richard Johnson was born in 1878 in Cornell, Illinois. He received a B.A. degree from Northwestern University in 1905 and an M.A. degree from Columbia University Teachers College in 1937. In 1906, Johnson sailed for China to serve as a missionary for the Methodist Episcopal Church. In China, he served as a pastor, educator and school administrator. He was active in famine and flood relief work, 1931-1936, and proposed a Rural Reconstruction Program adopted by the central government in 1933. Shortly after becoming the assistant director of the American Red Cross China Relief Unit, Johnson was taken prisoner by the Japanese in 1941. He was exchanged and returned to the United States in 1942. He died in Polo, Illinois on July 19, 1967.
Johnson, William Richard, 1878-1967
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the Johnson family.
Biographical / Historical
1849-1914 Sarah Esther Husted, mother of WRJ, born in Indiana and came to Illinois at an early age.
1851-1908 Benjamin R. Johnson, father of WRJ, born in Ruyville, Ohio; came to Illinois at the age of 2 in a prairie schooner; was a general storekeeper and banker in Cornell, Illinois. (The following are children of Sarah Esther and Benjamin R. Johnson: Estella, b. 1872, d. 1874; Franklin, b. 1874; Sidney Elmer, b. 1881; William Richard, b. 1878, d. 1967; Harry, b. 1883, d. 1950; Marcia (Lowell), b. 1886; Edward Amer, b. 1889; Lucille (Jones), b. 1892.)
1882 Ina Buswell Johnson, wife of WRJ, born in Illinois. Her parents were Joel Battie Buswell (1834-1905) and Laura Shoemaker Buswell (1843-1936).(The children of Joel Battie and Laura Shoemaker Buswell are: Clark, Emily (Thorpe), Elizabeth (Antrim) and James.)
1894 WRJ finished ninth grade in Cornell public school.
1897 Graduated from Pontiac High School, Illinois
1898-1899 Taught district school in Illinois
1899-1901 Worked as a cashier in the Cornell bank
1901 Entered Northwestern University, Evanston, Illinois
1905 IBJ and WRJ graduated from Northwestern, both with degrees in Liberal Arts.
1905-1906 WRJ worked as a fund raiser for the building campaign of the Y.M.C.A. at the University of Illinois.
1906 Laura Lillian, b. 1920 in Polo, Illinois, graduated from Ohio Wesleyan University, served in the Navy in World War II, awarded M.A. degree from University of Michigan, taught school, married Lt. Col. Clifford L. Woodliff, lived in Polo, Illinois with WRJ at the time of his death. William Buswell, b. 1908 in Kuling, later became a Methodist minister in California. Joel Benjamin, b. 1910 in Nanchang, later became a lawyer in Princeton, New Jersey. Clark Husted, b. 1913 in Nanchang, later named Foreign Director for McNeil Laboratories, then purchased the Zemmer Company in 1964 and sailed for China (Dec. 9) as a missionary for the Methodist Church. James Bashford, b. 1915 in Nanchang, graduated from Western Reserve Medical School, served in World War II, eventually practiced medicine in Greencastle, Indiana.
1907 Arrived in Shanghai and was ordained to the ministry of the Methodist Episcopal Church; began to study the Chinese language.
1908 Pastor and District Superintendent, Nanchang, Kiangsi Province.
1913 James Whitford Bashford writes about WRJ: "one of the ablest representatives of our church in central Asia or in the entire nation." (James W. Bashford was a bishop of the Methodist Church in China 1904-1915. See George Richmond Grose, James W. Bashford: Pastor, Educator, Bishop, (New York: The Methodist Book Concern, 1922).)
1915-1918 Principal, Nanchang Academy
1918-1919 Furlough. Secretary for Foreign Missions and Stewardship in the Methodist Centenary Movement, Denver, Colorado area.
1919-1920 Assistant Secretary of the Stewardship Dept., Methodist Committee on Conservation and Advance, New York City.
1921-1927 Principal, Nanchang Academy
1922 Red Cross refugee work
1924-1927 Executive Secretary, Kiangsi International Famine Relief, directing dike repair, famine relief program.
1927-1929 Furlough. Studied at Columbia University; Executive Secretary, China Famine Relief (New York City) during its first financial campaign.
1929-1936 Director of Religious Education, Nanchang Academy
1931-1936 Famine and flood relief work, directed part of the dike repair program financed by the American Wheat and Cotton Loan, 1931-1932.
1933 Made a survey for Generalissimo and Madame Chiang Kai-shek, outlining a Rural Reconstruction Program for Kiangsi Province which was adopted by central government and provincial authorities and put into operation. For Johnson's involvement in the Rural Reconstruction Program see While China Faced West, by James C. Thomson, Jr. (James C. Thomson, Jr. While China Faced West: American Reformers in Nationalist China, 1928-1937. (Cambridge, Mass.: Harvard University Press, 1969.))
1933-1936 Chairman, Board of Trustees of the Kuling Estate, participating in the rendition ceremonies January 1, 1936. (Kuling Estate was a summer resort which was administrated by the British as a part of the Concession of Kiukiang, but not returned with the Concession, under the Chen-O'Malley Agreement.)
1936-1937 Furlough. Columbia University Teachers College, M.A.
1937-1940. Returned to China without his family. District missionary, largely engaged in war-relief administration: hospitals and relief camps with industrial work and cooperatives.
1940 Furlough
1941 Lay Superintendent of the Canossa Hospital (later the Majama Hospital), a British Government Hospital for civilian wounded, during the siege of Hong Kong. Assistant Director, American Red Cross, China Relief Unit, in charge of Hong Kong office.
1941-1942 Prisoner of the Japanese, interned from January 5, 1942 until June 29, 1942 at Stanley Civilian Internment Camp.
1942 Exchanged at Lorenco Marques and returned to U.S. on the "Gripsholm."
1942-1949 Lectured for the U.S.O. in Army and Navy camps, in Rotary International Institutes, for Y.M.C.A. groups, crossing the United States four times. His lectures were arranged largely by the Redpath speakers' bureau.
1944 Speaker for the Community War Fund, Washington, D.C.
1946 Had given 361 addresses in twenty states.
1947-1952 Published various articles regarding China.
1954 Appeared before the Un-American Activities Committee of the U.S. House of Representatives, eighty-third Congress.
1950-1966 WRJ debated this issue through letters, articles and speeches. "During the course of the Kuomintang's decline, the reformers and their colleagues were soon torn by partisanship. In the war and postwar years, the Protestant missionary community became sharply divided--as did American officials and academics--on the question of loyalty to the Kuomintang regime. On the one side stood such indefatigable spokesmen for the Nationalists as Walter H. Judd ..., William R. Johnson... .Ranged against them were...other American missionaries, whose disillusionment with the Nationalists was intense..."(Thomson, While China Faced West, p. 242.)
1962 Presented with a medal by the Republic of China on behalf of Chiang Kai-shek. The award was given "in recognition of his meritorious contribution." (Box 50, Series V, Folder 19)
1963 Ina Buswell Johnson died in Polo, Illinois.
1967 Jul 19 William Richard Johnson died in Polo, Illinois.
Scope and Contents
I. Correspondence, 1836-1966, n.d.
II. Writings and Printed Material, 1906-1961, n.d.
III. Notes and Notebooks, 1887-1966.
IV. Financial and Legal Material, 1901-1966.
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1878-1966.
The first series, CORRESPONDENCE, is divided into two sections:
CORRESPONDENCE: FAMILY
CORRESPONDENCE: GENERAL
CORRESPONDENCE: FAMILY, dating from 1836 to 1966, includes the correspondence of many family members and gives detailed information about their activities. The letters, most of which are addressed to William and Ina Johnson, express the closeness of the family and in later years indicate an interest in preserving family records. The lives of the Johnson children are particularly elucidated by the correspondence, including their reactions to events in which they were involved and their reactions to their father's activities. The completeness and honesty of the family correspondence is very notable. Letters written regarding the settlement of Mrs. Johnson's estate after her death in 1963 reveal the misunderstanding, bitterness, and complications which emerged as Mr. Johnson worked out an agreeable solution. The family correspondence is also useful for the insights and observations about China which it includes. For example, in the spring of 1920 when Johnson was in New York during their furlough, he wrote to his wife concerning his conversation with the son of Bishop W.S. Lewis of China, referring to the difficulties blocking their return to China and conflicts encountered in China in the past.
CORRESPONDENCE: GENERAL (1852-1966) includes business as well as personal correspondence. Letters from college, missionary, and Chinese friends of William R. Johnson continue throughout. Johnson's work and involvements are highly visible through the correspondence. Perhaps the most significant period in the correspondence is the years spent in China (1906-1942). Johnson's detailed letters to his Bishops (in turn: James W. Bashford, L.J. Birney, Herbert Welch and W.E. Hammaker) describe financial, property, and mission matters, some relating to the annual conferences. Of particular interest is Johnson's involvement in the purchase of some land for the Methodist mission between the years 1912-1917 which eventually led to a court case. Johnson's relationship with Generalissimo and Madame Chiang Kai-shek is also revealed in the correspondence. He receives correspondence from Madame Chiang Kai-shek in 1934 and 1938, as well as several notes from her secretary. Johnson writes of his Plan for Rural Reconstruction in June 1933 and in 1927, 1938 and 1939 writes describing war conditions and refugee work.
During the years after his return from China the correspondence reflects Johnson's deep commitment to fighting communism. His conservative political concerns are very evident in correspondence with congressmen, senators, to the President of the United States, to magazine editors and church dignitaries. Letters regarding Johnson's publications and efforts to find financial backing for the mailing activities related to his political concerns are included in the correspondence. Notable in this section is Johnson's correspondence with Alfred Kohlberg regarding the American China Policy Association, with which Johnson was associated from 1945-1960, serving on its Board of Directors for several years.
Johnson also exchanges letters with former students and friends in China such as C.K. Shaw, principal of the Nanchang Academy. Personal and printed newsletters from fellow missionaries are also included.
Abraham Lincoln Nat'l. Republican Club
American China Policy Ass'n.
American Friends of the Captive Nations
American Friends of Vietnam
American Jewish League Against Communism
American Mercury
American Way
Association of Citizens' Councils
China Bulletin
Chinese News Service
Christian Beacon
Christian Children's Fund
Christian Educational Association
Christian Freedom Foundation
Christian Herald
Christian National Crusade
Church League of America
Circuit Riders, Inc.
Citizens' Council
Citizens' Foreign Aid Committee
Committee of One Million
Committee for Constitutional Government
Committee for the Preservation of State and Local Government
Congress of Freedom, Inc.
Constitution Clubs of Illinois
Cosmos Club
Council for Statehood
Defenders of the American Constitution
Embury-Heck Anniversary Committee
Everingham Company
Federation for Constitutional Government
For America
Free China Committee
Free Enterprise
Free Men Speak
Freedom Club
Freedom School, Inc.
"Heads Up"
Human Events
Independent American
International Cooperation Administration
International Council of Christian Churches
John Birch Society
Liberty Lobby
Methodist Challenge
National Conservative Party
National Economic Council, Inc.
National Review
New Leader
News and Views
Ohio Coalition of Patriotic Societies
Operation Brotherhood
Plain Talk
Public Action, Inc.
United States Flag Committee
We, the People
Young Americans for Freedom
The second series, WRITINGS AND PRINTED MATERIAL, is divided into two major categories: works by William R. Johnson and those written by others.
The first category contains a variety of material including translations, reports, bulletins, book reviews, published and unpublished articles and manuscripts, talks, sermons, and memoranda. Included also are some writings by other family members. The various dates of this material provide a key to the subject matter.
The second category contains those writings and printed material which were not written by WRJ, or his family members. This material includes minutes, reports, pamphlets, and journals, sometimes anonymous. Among the most interesting are the China Famine Relief news releases (1928).
The material of the third series, NOTES AND NOTEBOOKS, is varied and includes addresses, a card file, and diaries. The notes are class notes, rough drafts of writings, sermon notes, notes regarding current events, lecture and book notes. Some are written on individual sheets and others are in notebooks. Most of the material is dated. Included also are address lists, diaries, and notes by Ina Buswell Johnson.
FINANCIAL AND LEGAL MATERIAL, the fourth series, is divided between personal and non-personal material. The first category is the personal material of Mr. and Mrs. Johnson, and includes legal documents, bills, bank statements, canceled checks, receipts, tax forms, and daily accounts. This material provides information about the various philanthropic, political, and church-related organizations to which Johnson contributed.
The second category, non-personal material, contains financial and legal material regarding various groups, such as the Methodist Church and China Relief Work, with which Johnson was associated while in China. Budgets, reports, and financial agreements are included.
PERSONAL ITEMS AND MEMORABILIA, the final series, contains biographical and genealogical information regarding the families of Mr. and Mrs. Johnson, as well as a variety of other commemorative material.
Arrangement
I. Correspondence, 1836-1966, n.d.
II. Writings and Printed Material, 1909-1961
III. Notes and Notebooks, 1887-1966
IV. Financial and Legal Material, 1901-1966
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1878-1966
Anti-communist movements; Missions -- China; China -- History; Clergy; Educators; Missionaries; Bashford, J. W. (James Whitford), 1849-1919; Birney, L. J. (Lauress J.), 1871-1937; Chiang, Kai-shek, 1887-1975; Hammaker, Wilbur Emery, 1876-; Johnson, William Richard, 1878-1967; Kohlberg, Alfred, 1887-1960; Welch, Herbert, 1862-1969; American China Policy Association, Inc; Methodist Episcopal Church; Nanchang Academy
- Correspondence, 1836-1966, n.d.; Series I; 7' (26 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series is divided into two sections:
  CORRESPONDENCE: FAMILY
  The material in this section is arranged chronologically with telegrams following in chronological order. Letters, telegrams and fragments with no date (n.d.) are filed alphabetically by author at the end.
  CORRESPONDENCE: GENERAL
  This section is arranged chronologically with letters of importance listed on the folder headings. A few of the letters are neither to or from the Johnsons. When "Incl." is written on the folder heading, it indicates there are other letters included in the folder besides those that are mentioned. Almost every folder contains letters (usually carbon copies) from WRJ; this is not noted on the folder heading.
  Letters with no dates are filed alphabetically. Fragments are filed by date when available, or alphabetically by author. Telegrams are filed at the end of the correspondence.
  - Correspondence: Family
    - Letters to/from family, 1836 May 21-1903 (Box 1, Folder 1-20)
    - Letters to/from family, 1904-1912 (Box 2, Folder 21-33)
    - Letters to/from family, 1913-1935 (Box 3, Folder 34-55)
    - Letters to/from family, 1936-1941 (Box 4, Folder 55-69)
    - Letters to/from family, 1942-1949 (Box 5, Folder 70-87)
    - Letters to/from family, 1950-1957 (Box 6, Folder 88-107)
    - Letters to/from family, 1958-1964 (Box 7, Folder 108-123)
    - Letters to/from family, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 124-127)
    - Telegrams:, 1910-1963 (Box 8, Folder 128)
    - n.d.: Antrim, Elizabeth (Buswell) (Box 9, Folder 129)
    - n.d.: Buswell, Emma (Mrs. Clark) (Box 9, Folder 130)
    - n.d.: Buswell, Laura (Shoemaker) (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - n.d.: Buswell, Marion and Clara L. (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - n.d.: Husted, Jean (Box 9, Folder 133)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Edward Amer (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Elizabeth (Fink) (Box 9, Folder 135)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Franklin (Box 9, Folder 136)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Harry (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Ina (Buswell) (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - n.d.: Johnson, James Bashford (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Joan and Clark Husted (Box 9, Folder 140)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Joel Benjamin (Box 9, Folder 141)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Joyce (Hunt) (Box 9, Folder 142)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Martha Ellen (Rector) (Box 9, Folder 143)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Mary (Seldon) (Box 9, Folder 144)
    - n.d.: Johnson, Sarah Esther (Husted) (Box 9, Folder 145)
    - n.d.: Johnson, William Buswell (Box 9, Folder 146)
    - n.d.: Johnson, William Richard (Box 9, Folder 147)
    - n.d.: Jones, John L. (Box 9, Folder 148)
    - n.d.: Jones, Lucille (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 149)
    - n.d.: Lowell, Marcia (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 150)
    - n.d.: Lowell, Marcia (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 151)
    - n.d.: Thorpe, Emily (Buswell) (Box 9, Folder 152)
    - n.d.: Woodliff, Laura (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 153)
    - n.d.: Woodliff, Laura (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 154)
    - n.d.: Woodliff, Laura (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 155)
    - n.d.: Woodliff, Laura (Johnson) (Box 9, Folder 156)
    - n.d.: Misc. Grandchildren (Box 9, Folder 157)
    - n.d.: Misc. Nieces and Nephews (Box 9, Folder 158)
    - n.d.: Telegrams (Box 9, Folder 159)
    - Fragments: Antrim, Elizabeth (Buswell) (Box 10, Folder 160)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Edward Amer (Box 10, Folder 161)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Frank (Box 10, Folder 162)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Harry (Box 10, Folder 163)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Ina (Buswell) (Box 10, Folder 164)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Joel Benjamin (Box 10, Folder 165)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Mary (Seldon) (Box 10, Folder 166)
    - Fragments: Johnson, Sidney Elmer (Box 10, Folder 167)
    - Fragments: Johnson, William Buswell (Box 10, Folder 168)
    - Fragments: Johnson, William Richard (Box 10, Folder 169)
    - Fragments: Jones, Lucille (Johnson) (Box 10, Folder 170)
    - Fragments: Lowell, Marcia (Johnson) (Box 10, Folder 171)
    - Fragments: Woodliff, Laura (Johnson) (Box 10, Folder 172)
    - Fragments: Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 173)
  - Correspondence: General
    - Correspondence, 1852 (Box 11, Folder 174)
    - Re: Achievement in Pontiac Summer Normal School, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 175)
    - Re: College room-mate, 1902 (Box 11, Folder 176)
    - Re: SVM card, 1903 (Box 11, Folder 177)
    - Incl. re: YMCA, 1904 (Box 11, Folder 178)
    - Incl. from: Bishop J.W. Bashford, 1905 Jan-Jul (Box 11, Folder 179)
    - Incl. re: Job offers, 1905 Aug-Dec (Box 11, Folder 180)
    - Incl. re: Marriage, job, 1906 (Box 11, Folder 181)
    - Incl. re: Arrival in China, Appt. by Bishop Bashford, 1907 (Box 11, Folder 182)
    - Incl. from: J.R. Trindle, 1908 (Box 11, Folder 183)
    - Incl. to: Bishop Bashford, J.R. Trindle; re: Mission affairs, 1909 (Box 11, Folder 184)
    - Incl. from: O.S. Hubbard, 1910 Jan (Box 11, Folder 185)
    - Incl. to/from: Bishop Bashford, 1910 Feb-Aug (Box 11, Folder 186)
    - Incl. from: J.S. Vaughan, J.R. Trindle, 1910 Sep-Nov (Box 11, Folder 187)
    - Incl. to/from: Bishop Bashford, J.R. Trindle, 1911 Jan-May (Box 11, Folder 188)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford To: A.J. Bowen,From: J.R. Trindle, 1911 Jun-Sep (Box 11, Folder 189)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford Fr: J.S. Vaughan, 1911 Oct-Dec (Box 11, Folder 190)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, A.J. Bowen, re: Land purchase, 1912 Jan-Feb (Box 11, Folder 191)
    - Incl. fr: American Consular Service, Bishop Bashford, W.S. Lewis, J.R. Trindle; re: Land purchase, 1912 Mar-Apr (Box 11, Folder 192)
    - Incl. re: Land controversy, 1912 May (Box 11, Folder 193)
    - Incl. re: Land controversy, 1912 Jun-Jul (Box 11, Folder 194)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford Re: Land controversy, 1912 Aug-Oct (Box 11, Folder 195)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, to: C.F. Kupfer, re: Land contro versy, 1912 Nov-Dec (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, re: Land controversy, 1913 Jan-Mar (Box 12, Folder 197)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, re: Land controversy, Furlough of WRJ, 1913 Apr-Aug (Box 12, Folder 198)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.G. Vaughan, fr: Bishop Bashford, 1913 Sep-Dec (Box 12, Folder 199)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, re: Land settlement, 1914 Jan-May (Box 12, Folder 200)
    - Incl. to/fr: J.G. Vaughan re: Return to China, 1914 Jun-Dec (Box 12, Folder 201)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, W.S. Lewis, 1915 Jan-Mar (Box 12, Folder 202)
    - Incl. to: Bishop Bashford, W.S. Lewis, 1915 Apr-Dec (Box 12, Folder 203)
    - Incl. To/fr: J.W. Bashford, W.S. Lewis, fr: C.F. Kupfer, 1916 Jan-Dec (Box 12, Folder 204)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.S. Lewis, re: Nan chang Land case, 1917 Jan-Apr (Box 12, Folder 205)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.S. Lewis, C.F. Kupfer, fr: J.G. Vaughan, re: Nanchang Land case, 1917 May-Dec (Box 12, Folder 206)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Bashford, F.C. Gale to: W.S. Lewis, re: Furlough, 1918 Jan-Jul (Box 12, Folder 207)
    - Incl. to/fr: F.C. Gale, W.S. Lewis re: Methodist Centenary Movement, 1918 Aug-Sep (Box 12, Folder 208)
    - Incl. to/fr: F.C. Gale, 1918 Oct-Dec (Box 12, Folder 209)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.S. Lewis, Fr: F.C. Gale re: Death of Bishop Bashford, Centenary Movement, 1919 Apr-Jun (Box 12, Folder 211)
    - Incl. to/fr: F.C. Gale, to: A.J. Bowen, F.M. North, 1919 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 212)
    - Incl. to/fr: F.C. Gale, ret Conference, Centenary Movement, 1919 Sep-Dec (Box 12, Folder 213)
    - Incl. fr: F.C. Gale, J.G. Vaughan re: Centenary, return to China, 1920 Jan-Mar (Box 13, Folder 214)
    - Incl. to/fr: Fred R. Brown, fr: Ralph. Ward, re: Return to China, Centenary, 1920 Apr-Jul (Box 13, Folder 215)
    - Incl. to/fr: W.S. Lewis, re: Return to China, Centenary, 1920 Aug-Dec (Box 13, Folder 216)
    - Incl. to/fr: E.C. Perkins, E.L. Terman re: Centenary, Annual Meeting report, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 217)
    - Incl. to/fr: American Consul General re: Anti-Christian Movement, to: Bishop Birney ret purchase of Nanchang college site, re: illness of WRJ, 1922 (Box 13, Folder 218)
    - Incl. re: Illness of WRJ, 1923 (Box 13, Folder 219)
    - Incl. to/fr: American Consular Service ret political conditions Reports by C.F. Kupfer and WRJ Re: Famine Relief Committee, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 220)
    - Incl. to/fr: Bishop Birney, American Consular Service, 1925 Jan-Jun (Box 13, Folder 221)
    - Incl. to/fr: American Consular Service, Bishop Birney, 1925 Jul-Dec (Box 13, Folder 222)
    - Inc. to/fr: American Consular Service, Bishop Birney, 1926 Jan-May (Box 13, Folder 223)
    - Incl. to/fr: American Consular Service, Bishop Birney re: Siege of Nanchang, 1926 Jun-Sep (Box 13, Folder 224)